{"Topic": "Awards", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "The Arjuna Awards were instituted in the year", "op1": "1963", "op2": "1965", "op3": "1961", "op4": "1957", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The \u2018Dronacharya Award\u2019 is associated with", "op1": "Eminent Surgeons", "op2": "Famous Artists", "op3": "Sport Coaches", "op4": "Expert Engineers", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Nobel Prizes are not given for which of the following fields ?", "op1": "Physics", "op2": "Chemistry", "op3": "Peace", "op4": "Music", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The Pulitzer Prize is associated with which one of the following ?", "op1": "Environmental protection", "op2": "Olympic Games", "op3": "Journalism", "op4": "Civil Aviation", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "To encourage increase in the quality, quantity and availibility of food in the world, the World Food Prize was founded by", "op1": "Prof. M.S. Swaminathan", "op2": "UNDP", "op3": "Prof. Norman Borlaug", "op4": "WHO", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "For outstanding contribution to which one of the following fields is Shanti Swarup Bhatnagar Prize given?", "op1": "Literature", "op2": "Science", "op3": "Performing Arts", "op4": "Social Service", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following organisations gives the Kalinga Prize for popularising science?", "op1": "UNESCO", "op2": "CSIR", "op3": "UGC", "op4": "Ministry of Science and Technology", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Ramon Magsaysay awards are given in honour of former President of", "op1": "Indonesia", "op2": "Thailand", "op3": "New Zealand", "op4": "Philippines", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following awards is also known as Alternative Nobel Prize?", "op1": "Pulitzer Prize", "op2": "Right Livelihood Award", "op3": "Booker Prize", "op4": "Ramon Magsaysay Award", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which is highest gallantry award for the personnel of armed forces in India?", "op1": "Ashoka Chakra", "op2": "Maha Vir Chakra", "op3": "Param Vir Chakra", "op4": "Kirti Chakra", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following States confers the Kabir Samman, Kalidas Samman and Tansen Samman?", "op1": "Rajasthan", "op2": "Uttar Pradesh", "op3": "Bihar", "op4": "Madhya Pradesh", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is NOT an award in the field of literature?", "op1": "Sahitya Akademi Award", "op2": "Jnanpith Award", "op3": "Jamnalal Bajaj Award", "op4": "Saraswati Samman", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In whose memory have Manav Sewa Awards for Service to Children instituted by Government of India?", "op1": "Indira Gandhi", "op2": "Rajiv Gandhi", "op3": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "op4": "Mahatma Gandhi", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The reputed Man Booker Prize is awarded every year to the", "op1": "Best novel in English by a citizen of U.K., the Commonwealth or Ireland", "op2": "Best novel in English by anyone in the world", "op3": "Best novel in English by a citizen of U.K., the U.S.A or Canada", "op4": "Best novel in English by a citizen of any country of Europe or Asia", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Nirmal Gram Puraskars are awards given to villages which", "op1": "are 100% open defecation free", "op2": "provide clean drinking water to villagers", "op3": "are free from communal distinction", "op4": "abolish untouchability", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following awards is given to journalists?", "op1": "Dadasaheb Phalke Award", "op2": "Meghdoot Award", "op3": "Jamnalal Bajaj Award", "op4": "Chameli Devi Jain Award", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following awards is known as Mathematicians' Nobel Prize?", "op1": "Turing Award", "op2": "Abel Prize", "op3": "Rolf Nevanlinna Prize", "op4": "Wolf Prize", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the highest gallantry award in India given for bravery NOT in the face of enemy?", "op1": "Ashoka Chakra", "op2": "Kirti Chakra", "op3": "Mahavir Chakra", "op4": "Shaurya Chakra", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which of the following years was the first Bharat Ratna awarded?", "op1": "1953", "op2": "1954", "op3": "1955", "op4": "1951", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following following awards is NOT associated with films?", "op1": "Academy Award", "op2": "BAFTA Award", "op3": "Emmy Award", "op4": "Golden Globe Award", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In which of the following fields is the Dhanvantari Award given?", "op1": "Literature", "op2": "Medicine", "op3": "Social work", "op4": "Journalism", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following awards is USUALLY given to only one person in a year?", "op1": "Sahitya Akademi Award", "op2": "Sangeet Natak Akademi Award", "op3": "Padma Award", "op4": "Jnanpith Award", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "At which of the following film festivals is the Golden Peacock award given to the best film?", "op1": "International Film Festival of India", "op2": "Cannes Film Festival", "op3": "Venice Film Festival", "op4": "Childrens' Film Festival of India", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Rajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna Award, Arjuna Awards and other sports awards are given to sportspersons on August 29 every year which is the birthday of -", "op1": "K.D. Jadhav", "op2": "Polly Umrigar", "op3": "Rajiv Gandhi", "op4": "Major Dhyanchand", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following prizes is given to a person who has \"made an exceptional contribution to affirming life's spiritual dimension\"?", "op1": "Pulitzer Prize", "op2": "Templeton Prize", "op3": "Turing Award", "op4": "Gandhi Peace Prize", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following organisations/states awards the Vyas Samman and Saraswati Samman in the field of literature?", "op1": "Madhya Pradesh", "op2": "KK Birla Foundation", "op3": "Tata Education and Development Trust", "op4": "Uttar Pradesh", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Booker Prize is given in the field of -", "op1": "Medicine", "op2": "Adventure", "op3": "Fiction writing", "op4": "Science", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Sabin Award is given for the conservation of", "op1": "snakes", "op2": "amphibians", "op3": "arctic animals", "op4": "insects", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The highest Indian decoration for showing valour and gallantry in the war is ::", "op1": "Param Vishistha Seva Medal", "op2": "Ashoka Chakra", "op3": "Param Vir Chakra", "op4": "Mahavir Chakra", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who among the following non-Indians was conferred India\u2019s highest national award \u2018Bharat Ratna\u2019 ?", "op1": "Sam Nujoma", "op2": "Martin Luther King", "op3": "Zubin Mehta", "op4": "Nelson Mandela", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following awards is instituted by the UNESCO ?", "op1": "Nehru Award for international understanding", "op2": "Kalinga Prize", "op3": "Arjuna Award", "op4": "Dronacharya Award", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The Bharatendu Harishchandra awards have been instituted by the :", "op1": "Hindi Sahatiya Sammelan", "op2": "Government of Uttar Pradesh", "op3": "Government of Madhya Pradesh", "op4": "Union Ministry of Information and Broadcasting", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Mahathir Award for Global Peace instituted in 2013 has been named after a former Prime Minister of", "op1": "Indonesia", "op2": "Philippines", "op3": "Malaysia", "op4": "Thailand", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The name Savitri Khanolkar is associated with design of which of the following awards?", "op1": "Param Vir Chakra", "op2": "Bharat Ratna", "op3": "Padma Vibhushan", "op4": "Ashok chakra", "Answer": 4}]}